United we stand. Divided we fall.
Captain America: Civil War is a adventure, action,
science fiction film directed by Joe Russo.
Following the events of Age of Ultron, the collective governments of the
world pass an act designed to regulate all superhuman activity.
This polarizes opinion amongst the Avengers, causing two factions to side with Iron Man
or Captain America, which causes an epic battle between former allies.
Steve Rogers / Captain America, played by Chris Evans.
Tony Stark / Iron Man, played by Robert Downey Jr..
Natasha Romanoff / Black Widow, played by Scarlett Johansson.
Bucky Barnes / Winter Soldier, played by Sebastian Stan.
Sam Wilson / Falcon, played by Anthony Mackie.
Lieutenant James Rhodes / War Machine, played by Don Cheadle.
Captain America: Civil War is a 2016 American superhero film based on the Marvel Comics character Captain
America, produced by Marvel Studios and distributed by Walt Disney Studios Motion Pictures.
It is the sequel to Captain America: The First Avenger (2011) and Captain America: The
Winter Soldier (2014), and the 13th film in the Marvel Cinematic Universe (MCU).
The film was directed by Anthony and Joe Russo from a screenplay by the writing team of Christopher Markus and Stephen McFeely, and stars Chris Evans as Steve Rogers / Captain America alongside an ensemble cast including Robert Downey Jr., Scarlett
Johansson, Sebastian Stan, Anthony Mackie, Don Cheadle, Jeremy Renner, Chadwick Boseman, Paul Bettany, Elizabeth Olsen, Paul Rudd, Emily VanCamp, Marisa Tomei, Tom Holland, Frank Grillo, Martin Freeman, William Hurt, and Daniel Brühl.
In Captain America: Civil War, disagreement over international oversight of the Avengers fractures the team
into two opposing factions—one led by Steve Rogers and the other by Tony Stark (Downey).
Development of Civil War began in late 2013 when Markus and McFeely began writing the screenplay, which borrows concepts from the 2006 comic book
storyline "Civil War" while also focusing on story and character elements from the previous Captain America films to conclude the trilogy.
Following positive reactions to The Winter Soldier, the Russo
brothers were brought back to direct in early 2014.
The film's title and premise were revealed in October 2014, along with Downey's
involvement as Stark; additional cast members joined in the following months.
Principal photography began in April 2015 at Pinewood
Atlanta Studios in Fayette County, Georgia.
It continued in the Metro Atlanta area before concluding in Germany in August 2015, with the film being
the first to use IMAX's digital 2D cameras (for the film's central airport fight sequence).
Visual effects were provided by nearly 20 different studios.
Captain America: Civil War held its world premiere at the Dolby Theatre in Hollywood, Los Angeles, on April 12,
2016, and was released in the United States on May 6, as the first film in Phase Three of the MCU.
The film was a commercial success, grossing over $1.1 billion worldwide, becoming the highest-grossing film of 2016, and received
positive reviews from critics, with praise for the performances (particularly Evans and Downey), action sequences, and themes.
A fourth film, Captain America: Brave New World (2025), is a continuation of Marvel Studios' Disney+ series
The Falcon and the Winter Soldier (2021), following Mackie's Sam Wilson as Captain America.
The film explores themes of superhero, based on comic,
sequel, super soldier, aftercreditsstinger.
The tone is thought_provoking.